Thank you so much, Salvi and uh Amy.
That was a fantastic fireside chat and
welcome to Galverse uh education crisis
day one and I've been loving the uh
round table so far. But today or should
I say right now we have a fantastic list
of panelists with us today where we're
going to be talking about the future
learner what they need to know. So, I'm
really looking forward to this round
table discussion. Uh, panelists, what
we're going to do is we're going to do a
quick introduction from each of
yourselves. Uh, 30 seconds to a minute
and then once everyone's been
introduced, then we'll get straight into
the questions. So, we'll start with uh
Stephanie and then we'll head over to uh
Coach Pulo um which I remember you from
last time Paulo. So, it's great to see
you again as well. Um, and also Dr.
Venue as well has just joined us. Great
to see you as well, Dr. Venue. Um, but
yeah, we'll start with you, Stephanie.
Great. And, uh, great to see you again
as well.
>> Great to see you as well. Uh, thank you
for having me. I'm super excited about
this topic because I've been actively
telling people about this as much as
possible. I'm Stephanie Sylvester,
co-founder of Avatar Buddy, and we make
AI agents and digital twins to help
amplify employees and people to be their
best selves so that they can um increase
productivity and ultimately spend have
more time to spend with other humans.
>> Great to have you with us, Stephanie,
and welcome to Galas once again. Uh,
Coach Polo, uh, great to see you again
as well, uh, whilst he's on his phone
right there. Um, do you want to do a
quick introduction yourself? Uh, those
who don't know you.
>> Okay. Hello. I'm Paulo Mandes. I'm from
Brazil, but I live currently been living
in Cape Town, South Africa. And yeah,
I'm super excited about it. AI is here.
We need to embrace it. I believe is
coming to help us. We're never going to
be replaced because AI can make our work
easier and simpler and then we can
dedicate more to the human connection.
So I'm super excited to be part of this
panel and to learn more also.
>> Paulo, thank you so much for being with
us today. Devon, great to see you once
again as well. Been a while, but uh
yeah, please introduce yourself for
those who don't know who you are.
Likewise, likewise, always good to see
you. Uh, my name is Devin Baldwin. I am
a WebXR engineer and also educator. Um,
just simple and plain as that. I am a
creative technologist. I help people and
companies educate their people on how to
educate
more so than often.
>> Love it, Deon. Thank you so much. That's
such a speed quick introduction. Like
that was like the speed of light. Not
joking. Uh Dr. Venue, uh we're going to
head over to you now. Please introduce
yourself and then we'll go over to Nanda
next.
>> Hi.
>> Great to see you.
>> Okay. And today are you consulting?
>> We can't hear you Dr. Venue. Um it's
very like quiet and muffled. So we'll
come back to you very shortly and
Niranda please introduce yourself and
also welcome to Galas and also if you
just want to tilt your camera just
slightly down so we can see more of you.
There we go Narend thank you very much
please introduce yourself.
>> Thanks uh Russell thanks for having me
in this discussion. So uh my name is
Narendra Edi. I'm working as a lead
software engineer at Credential. Uh here
in credential in technology uh we use
lot of AI tools. So I wanted to share
some of my experience that might help
for the future learners. So and uh I'm
really excited uh to be part of this
discussion.
>> I'm looking forward to hearing what you
have to say Narenda and uh it's great to
also have you with us. Uh Arrestus uh
great to see you once again as well. Uh
please introduce yourself and also
welcome back once again.
>> Hello everyone. Hopefully you can hear
me nice and uh loud
>> loud and clear this time. Yes.
>> So my name is Orestu. I come from
Greece. I'm located in Vahen,
Netherlands. I'm the founder uh of a
company that is called Digifas in which
we are researching
disruptive and digital transformation
for a cross variety of sectors
agriculture, education, healthcare and
also metaverse application. I'm a an
artist entrepreneur. I produce music and
uh fine art, but also my background lies
in bios engineering, IT and creative
technologist.
Multi-talented as always, Arrest is
great to see you again as well. And last
but not least, Zana. Uh I don't know if
this is your first time or not, but this
is the first time I've met you. So hello
and welcome to Gavas and please
introduce yourself.
>> Of course. Nice to meet you, Russell. My
name is Zay English. I am a former
science teacher turned data analyst and
I have spent the last couple of years
focusing more on how AI is interacting
in both the public and private sector. I
typically work with clients whether
they're government clients, private
clients or even nonprofit clients on
trying to figure out AI policy and
implementation. And I'm really here
today because my focus is in education.
I am one of the things I am really
looking at and really researching is how
AI is being applied to the education
field and how we are using AI to educate
learners not just students in high
school but at all levels and ranges. I'm
very excited to be on this panel with
everyone and to meet everyone and I hope
that our gather will be well. I'm
looking forward to discussion as well as
learning every from everyone here.
Absolutely Zanna and thank you so much
for joining us and welcome also. Uh and
then last but not least I guess I'll
have to introduce myself now and then
we've got to actually sorry Dr. Venue
you're back again please introduce
yourself.
>> Hi and you know I'm working on a
enterprise
solutions and program
>> we're still having difficulties with
your microphone Dr. Venue. I'm apologies
for that. Um, so I'm going to introduce
myself. My name is Russell. I'm the
co-founder of Just Verify, also global
affairs director at Galvas. Um, and Just
Verify is focused on uh building the
trust infrastructure for AI. Uh, we're
focused on verifying the integrity and
trustworthiness of AI models to allow
you to have your own choices and your
own uh on what AI you want to adopt uh
rather than being told what to trust or
you know being blindly trusting or
something. So um that's what we
basically do in a nutshell at just
verify. Um so anyway let's get into the
questions. So question one uh how do we
define the future learner and how are
they different? I think this is such an
important question because as you all
know we're all individual learners
ourselves. We constantly study every
single day. Well I do at least anyway.
Um but um yeah I think it's such an
important question. So, uh, I think
we'll start with Paulo on this one
because I'm curious to hear what you
have to say, Paulo, and then we'll go
over to Stephanie after.
>> All right, that's a great question.
Thank you, Russell. Great to be here
again. And you know, I remember a few
years back where my son was in high
school, finishing high school, my
youngest son now 17 years old, and he
was required to take a laptop to to
school with him because all the material
was being done online.
>> And I mean, I know in America and Europe
that's old news, but here in Cape Town,
South Africa, there was in a public
school there was news, right? there was
a new thing.
>> Yeah. And now he studies online with AI
teaching
>> and he has occasional the tests are done
with actual live teachers but all the
teaching is done through AI and I
remember who remembers here the Jacksons
the cartoon the Jetsons
>> we're showing our age right but you know
I have this vision of a world where AI
is an incredible tool to help us
identify what learning uh uh styles each
student has and then be able to cater
for each student's different style.
That's what I have been experienced with
my two sons. One is graduated, the other
one is doing now his last year in high
school. And the way they study is
completely different. The way they learn
is completely different. And because the
younger one is having this experience
now with AI, we took him from a school
setup where he was labeled as a troubled
student, couldn't focus, couldn't pay
attention, couldn't follow up with the
curriculum to now being a a top level
student with the new system parallel
using parallel with AI. So I don't know
if I'm answering exactly what you wanted
as a as an answer there
>> but you know to me the experience of
>> AI in identifying what our unique
students are unique learners I believe
that AI caters for students that are
unique individuals that want to learn
and we're breaking away from the old
system that is a possibility that I see
>> it's very interesting Paulo because it's
also like a hybrid hybrid model, right?
Think about it. Like
I know obviously it's you know we we
I don't know Cape Town so I can't talk
on Cape Town but I know in general um
you know people are using computers
every day you know we're talking about
um phones every day etc etc. So you know
if we're defining what a future learner
is could that potentially be let's say a
hybrid learner could that be an AI
literate learner? Could that be um an an
AI assisted learner? Like you know how
it's kind of hard to define what a
future learner is when it comes to the
AI age. So I I think what you're
touching upon there where you're saying
computers are coming in for the first
time. Now AI is coming in for the first
time within Cape Town. And it's like you
know how do we for other countries not
just the first world countries but also
the third world countries how do we
distribute that evenly and making sure
everyone has is having a chance to learn
right Paulo? Yeah, there there are so
many tools online available. I mean
the the we all heard the expression that
you know we live in a global village,
right? With Tik Tok and Instagram and
the social media, internet in general,
we all exposed to the same tools that
are available now to learn about AI.
>> So I agree with you. I believe that the
the new stu the new learner is a hybrid
learner. It's somebody
>> when I speak of my son being 16 17 years
old, he he was brought up. AI to him is
part of his education system. That was
perhaps the the message that I wanted to
bring about. You know, AI to him is is
part of his learning experience. To me,
being 50 something years old is an
experience. I'm learning AI. To him, AI
is to him what working with a cell phone
was to me 20 years ago.
>> Right? So uh the the students I see you
laughing Stephanie right we go through
the same challenge you know back back 10
20 years ago we would joke about oh you
want to learn how to go online on your
cell phone or how to do things on your
cell phone ask a 14y old right now we
having the same experience with 14 15 16
year old students on AI I dare to say a
12y old my my my
son's best friend is a 12year-old has a
12-year-old little boy, little brother,
sorry, little brother, and and he comes
here and he connects everything for us.
He was teaching me how to use CL AI
where all I knew was JTPT and Gemini
from Google, right? And he teach me how
to code on CL. I'm like, what? Too much
for me, right? 12 years old.
>> Yeah, that's crazy. That's crazy. the
new the new the new learner is a hybrid
learner for sure.
>> 100% agree. And uh Stephie, let's bring
you into this conversation. Um I'm
curious to hear a your perspectiveness,
but also b you know when we're talking
about avatar buddies, right? Could we
potentially be having, you know, every
single individual person having their
own avatar buddy for education even or
something like that even? Well, if I
have my way, every single person would
have an AI buddy that helps them,
supports them, and um ensures that they
maintain equilibrium because at
equilibrium, that's when we're our best.
And obviously um we started this because
we wanted to be able to help people be
the best versions of themselves. With
that said,
um when you think about learning today,
it's very wrote. It's very much the
person who can write the best, who can
take the best tests, those are the
people that are considered smart. And
what that does is it overlooks a vast um
sector of people. with AI. Um, that will
no longer uh be a differentiator because
if you have a a a properly configured AI
tool like I have an AI editor, an editor
buddy that um is configured to help me
write and my writing has vastly improved
since I started using it and so my ideas
are being communicated more efficiently
and effectively.
Um before I was at a disadvantage. um if
somebody can memorize something for a
test again, right? We're not going to be
having to give tests for you to recalls
um information. We're going to be having
to give test to um show that you have
content knowledge and demonstrating of
content knowledge is way more complex.
And most of the time teachers don't have
the um the time or the wherewithal to be
able to administer those tests. AI can
administer those tests ongoing
um in a much faster way. Um, we're
working on a solution that we're calling
qualitative student assessment where the
AI can go look at your um your exam
results at the exam at the question
level across exams across courses and
based on whatever goal you're trying to
accomplish tell you whether where your
content um where you have content
deficiency. So no longer do we get these
students that are be that are getting
B's and have anywhere from 17 uh 15 to
17% content deficiency and we normally
cheer when somebody gets a B and move
them forward but that means that now we
can actually drill in because of AI. So
I think that in the future people are
going to need to know how to learn. So
there was a time when I was going to
school, they taught us how to learn. Now
I don't think that they're being taught
how to learn just based on interacting
with people. The moment a uh the the
sequence of events don't happen as the
way it's supposed to, you see people
going sideways, stopping and not knowing
what the next steps are. And that's
that's an indication of somebody that
doesn't know how to learn. And with AI,
you will need to know how to learn. Um,
and I also think that AI will require
greater
emotional intelligence, the ability to
do interpersonal
um, interaction. And I I I profess that
the future of learning should be
predicated on virtue 8 years old that
your focus on um emotional skills,
selfcluding, self self-management,
self-control,
self um self- agency. And then after
that we start teaching you uh content
information technical skills because if
you have those skills then learning
becomes easier. You have a desire to
learn. There's not a a tussle with the
with the the um teachers to learn. So I
can see that AI pushing this and making
the it not a dream anymore but a greater
sense of urgency and the students whose
parents allowed them to embrace this new
way of learning will excel much much
faster and it will have no bearing on
their social economic background and as
I travel around the world um and I go to
South Africa I'm actually really really
impressed by the level of advanced
technologically they are. I mean, I I I
went to Africa for six weeks and I used
just my cell phone to pay and I was
buying things from people from the side
of the street. I can't even do that in
Miami. So, just just a reset for people
that if you really want to know where AI
is going to go, you need to go spend
time in Africa because that's where
they're really doing some really cool,
innovative, different things and
winning. Yeah, they do. And one thing I
know about Africa is they also doing a
lot of background about blockchain and
crypto and everything like that as well.
So, but anyway, that's a whole different
discussion. Um, but yeah, I I completely
agree with you. Um, you know, I think
two things. One, um, remaining curious.
Um, no matter who you are, always be
curious, always be curious about
learning, always be curious about what
something is, always question it, etc.
and and two um you know when we're
talking about you know learning do like
I don't think any of us ever stop
learning so to speak right I mean we're
talking about life experiences we're
talking about um even just like learning
in general so I mean like for example
the UK government here has given 10
million um is going to educate 10
million people here in the UK by 2030
right in and in order to have them to
have AI literacy etc so and obviously
officials certification. But anyway, the
point I'm getting at is um you know,
education is extremely important no
matter who you are, what your background
is or where you're from, right? And I
think always remaining curious and
always being um curious in terms of
what's happening, what's going on. I
think that's fundamental and is like the
the the bottom line in terms of you know
learning more. So especially in the age
of AI. So let's go on to uh next
question now which is what foundational
knowledge must remain non-negotiable to
the future learners. So Devon I can see
you nodding your head over there so I'll
I'll tag you in on this one and then
we'll go to you next Zena and then uh
Arrestus and Narenda will head over to
you very shortly.
Deian over to you.
Thank you my friend and I just wanted to
also clarify and kind of also
agree with what you said. It's not in
pertaining directly within the context
of students because we all are students
of life. We learn every single day
through our experiences. So we are the
future learners as well. But you know
some things do not become optional just
because AI exists.
literacy,
numeracy, scientific reasoning,
historical context, communication, like
ethical reasoning. All these things
>> are very important core foundations
>> for the future learner as far as they
still need to read deeply. They still
need to write clearly, reason
quantitatively
and judge the quality,
you know, of what they consume because
ultimately it is a content
firestorm. It's just constantly AI and
just the world that we live in today, we
consume a lot of information. So 100%
>> it it'll be very important to have these
core foundations
solidified so we can or they can you
know decipher what is real what is not
what is good what is bad and that's also
subjective itself but
I just feel like those are just some
core non-negotiables for future learners
that will be important to making sure
that they could function within this
next phase of life.
you do bring up some really interesting
points and you know it also makes me
think about the sort of AR and XR
glasses right you know when we're
looking at them you know I mean some
person um I remember like he was um this
was this was a use case that happened
but uh some there was interviewing some
person because he they did a crime and
basically what they did was they caught
him talking to the AI on the glasses on
how to respond in the interview and they
didn't notice until they got to about
the second or third interview that they
were speaking to AI on the glasses. So
anyway, what what's the point that I'm
getting at? Like I think you know what
you're saying there, the non-negotiables
absolutely agree with, but also is there
also going to be new non-negotiables
like for example that sort of use case I
just told you there. Could there also be
new ones like that too as well, Darvin?
>> Well, I mean absolutely. I mean, with
the technology that we have today and
the technology that we're going to have,
there's a lot of slippery slopes
ethically and
>> technologically
like
using glasses in
legal proceedings to talk to AI.
The number one is crazy work. Like you
got to be really desperate or really
just not know.
>> Yeah. My lawyer's AI and glasses.
>> Yeah. Like I'm defending myself. It's me
and me and my meta glasses. No, that's
that's that's
really funny. Um but yeah, there there
is a slippery slope because
ultimately
it goes back to one of the one of the
gather verses that we had a while back
>> about constantly just agreeing to these
terms of services. We we don't know what
liberties or what different faculties
that we are surrendering at this point.
So when we do things like use our
glasses within these legal proceedings,
we're not exactly sure what we're
implicating ourselves in or
or if that could be used against us
later, but that's a that's a different
conversation.
>> Absolutely. And Zena, I want to bring
you on this conversation um from your
point of view and from your lens or
maybe even your own personal experience.
to say um what foundation knowledge must
remain non-negotiable to the future
learners from maybe even you or even for
other future learners that you maybe
teach or or a part of or in even the
class you get my drift what what is what
is what is from your point of view from
that sort of side of things
>> thank you for the question and I'm just
going to say I think Stephanie and Devon
really hit the point on the
of talking about critical thinking
skills being incredibly important.
Allowing or teaching students and people
how to think, how to learn, how to work
through a problem.
Giving or having our students or having
future learners understand the
foundational content knowledge. um rope
memory, being able to in the moment pull
information from past information or
past learnings that they've had,
building knowledge from the ground up.
From my own point of view, what we
oftentimes are now seeing is that people
are beginning to offload that process
onto AI. And that is the thing that we
really want to prevent people from
happening. We want people to use AI as a
partner, not as a crush or not in a
sense, we're using it to get through
things because one of the big things
about AI is that AI hallucinates.
It gets things wrong. Um, so in addition
to what Devon was saying about having
people be able to read, we really need
to teach our future learners to be
investigators, to be skeptics, to be
able to go and check, to have the
foundational knowledge to know how to go
and reference information. So, showing
my age back in the day, I used to I grew
up in a time in day and time where I was
told I could not use Wikipedia to site
anything, but I could use the sources
that Wikipedia cited
>> and going and being uh be able to fact
check things. One of the things that I
def I really am very big on now is
teaching people especially in this day
and age and even going in the future is
going to have new types of media
literacy. Um Devon touched on literacy.
Media literacy is so big mainly because
the fact in addition to we have to worry
about AI hallucinating or sometimes
making up whole articles,
whole journals, we also have to worry
about deep fakes and videos because
people also learn by watching the news,
by watching content. Well, how do I know
this video was not AI generator? How do
I know this person who created this
video um is a trustworthy source or the
information that's being given to me in
this video is trustworthy? So we have to
teach students to be able to naturally
investigate that knowing where to go and
how to kind of go through the
investigative process of checking our
information, checking our stats,
verifying our information, which I think
in the age of AI that is going to be
something that's going to be a real
challenge to do. And it's going to
involve for in my I know this is getting
a little bit off topic. It's going to
involve not just educators, but it's
going to involve communities, policy
makers in order to create and make sure
that we have a good foundational
knowledge base to teach people and for
people to keep learning. Le
>> let's let's dive into some of that a bit
more. Um, you know, we we we're talking
about deep fakes. Um, you know, let's
let's kind of dive into that. Let's go,
but let's also dive into sort of the
misinformation, disinformation, etc. as
well. We all know that misinformation,
disinformation has been around for a
very long time. Um when we when we when
we kind of dive into into that aspect um
you know we have recursive learning
right going on right now. If you don't
know what recursive learning is
basically AI training AI right in a
nutshell with different data. So my
question is is if we have this frenzy of
defects, misinformation, disinformation,
etc., and it's all getting worse, and
then we also have synthetic data also
adding to that mix as well and adding
more misinformation and disinformation.
Isn't this going to eventually just
spiral out of control? And then we don't
know what to believe like as in what we
see, what we hear, what we do, what we
learn as well, right? And also like, you
know, it's just going to get worse. So
Zena, my question to you is,
is this just going to get worse? Like,
as in, can people actually truly learn
from AI if we have this recursive
learning going on?
>> It's funny, and I'm so glad you asked
that question because as someone who
works with data, that is one of the
things that we ask ourselves the
question all the time because AI is
built off of the data that goes into the
model. So, as you pointed out, if we're
getting bad information, if the
information is not truly verifiable or
it's synthetic data, it's not real data,
what exactly are we creating our outputs
on? And to that question, we that is
something to actually worry about. But
what I would say is that when we're
creating AI models, we actually need to
streamline
what data is going into the model.
Instead of trying to feed the model
everything,
we should make it so that AI is that we
have an AI that is specifically for
medical knowledge. An AI that is
specifically that works with
architecture instead of trying to make
it be for everything. Because when you
open
more and you when you open or you
basically input more data in it that
it's not it's once you get start adding
large quantities of data it becomes
harder and harder and harder to check.
Whereas if you're just dealing with a
small sample
>> oh Zena you're breaking up then
>> Zena you're breaking up easier the
talking about
>> Oh okay you're breaking up. We'll we'll
we'll pause there. Zana, thank you so
much for sharing that. Uh we'll tag you
in just a minute, Stephanie. Um just one
thing I want to add as well. Um if you
think about and just in very simple
terms, if you think about the context
windows that you're using right within
chat GBT within Gemini, yes, we can ZA
um so but if you think about like the
context windows like when you're using
chat GBT, when you're using Gemini, when
you're using multiple other um any other
models, cloud etc. as it goes over time
because it keeps going and going and
going and going and going in the chat
eventually it gets to the point where it
starts telling you wrong things it then
starts going oh well I don't I don't I
don't remember that sorry all these kind
of sort of thing happen so just to give
you a bit of context of what Zena is
discussing about if you use chat GPD
yourself you'll understand that after a
while it's just like okay sol new chat
right so um thank you very much Zana for
sharing your thoughts Stephanie we'll
hand over to you apologies about that.
Um but yeah, please share your thoughts
quickly.
>> So I I totally agree that those um
predictions are coming fast and furious
with us, but there's also a way um I
think back to the beginning of the
internet time. So, I'm definitely dating
myself. And we were like, everybody, we
should just make this big big big big
wild
wide web that everything is in there.
And then we quickly realized that that
was not going to be um tenable and we
went to portals. And so what we're doing
now is data vaults, data vaults of
content that's interrelated or
specialized. and then
AI agents that are highly trained for
one or two specific task. So not a
generalist but a very specific thing. If
you take uh the field of uh finance, you
would have about five or six AI agents
that are helping you get the work done
because each one is specialized. And
when you do that, hallucination goes
down. Um because the data has been
verified, it's clean. Secondly, because
you're telling the AI what it's doing
and it's highly specialized, you don't
need to give it complex prompting for it
to give you back the in the the results
almost instantaneously. So instead of
asking it five or six iteration, you can
ask it maybe one two uh questions and it
will produce exactly what you're looking
for. And that's where I see the future
of AI going. And when you move in that
direction, you must have humans in the
loop. And with a solution like that,
with humans in the loop, that's what
restores the integrity of AI again. And
so I don't see how continuing to be
build bigger and bigger models gets us
to that. It's going to be smaller and
smaller and specialized models like how
we have portals. I mean, we don't even
think about portals, but there was a
time where portals was like a new novel
thing to do, and now everybody has a
portal. Nobody even thinks about it.
>> Yeah. And I I mean, even I do agree
specialized models are are better. Even
specialized models still have their
issues. Um, for example, they can't
always call tools. You know, there's
like anywhere between 2 to 6% chance of
it not being able to call the correct
tool. Um there are there are other
issues um within a system or workflow
that can go wrong but to the point of
the foundational of what you're saying
Stephanie are smaller models definitely
better than bigger models overall in
terms of what they specialize and what
they do for sure 100% agree with that um
just depending on what your use case is
but um you know we could get into you
know cross verification analysis and all
that kind of sort of stuff too but the
point is is you know I do agree what
Stephanie's saying and and Zena what
you're saying too right in terms of the
the reoccursive learning and the data
and everything like that as well you
know there's there's just a big problem
around all this and and one thing um
what we do at just verify which is
fundamental is verification so that's
kind of like what we do as I like to say
just verify is basically the bread and
butter is basically we do what we say on
the tin we verify everything so um but
anyway let's get to the next question um
so the next question is how Can we
cultivate discernment in the age of
information overload? Uh, Arrestus,
we're going to go to you and then
Narenda, we're going to go to you next.
And thank you so much for your patience,
both of you. I really appreciate that as
we've been having very heavy discussion.
Um, but the rest, please share us your
thoughts.
>> To begin with, thank you all of uh the
speakers for the useful information. Um,
this question is correlated with the
previous one. So uh we can cultivate uh
discernment in the age of information
overload with many uh ways.
First and foremost critical and slow
thinking I think is what uh um is the
first one in the the list of
prioritization. Uh the source evaluation
where are we getting the input but also
the output of these models. um the
pattern recognition
if we see multiple patterns that they
are um um let's say repeated um then we
have to like critically think about
these patterns
um
metalarning as a term uh which is like
knowing how
and um in general
The critical thinking I think is the
basic one uh that we should embrace uh
because in most of the times uh in the
age of uh restless and uh constant
information overload I think critical
thinking is what is overshadowed.
>> I I I also think
and let me ask you this question arrest
and maybe you can give me a good answer.
Do you think it's maybe also good that
we learn in incrementals rather than
trying to like take everything in all at
once?
>> I take that as yes.
>> Okay. Yes, that's the obvious uh answer,
right? Uh for sure. Yeah, that's an
obvious answer
on it.
>> Nanda, let's bring you into this
conversation as well. Um you know when
we talk about the age of information
overload
um you know you have royally built some
incredible tools um architected numerous
uh you know AI models etc. So how do we
how how can we cultivate the discernment
in the age of the information overload
so to speak from your point of view?
>> Sure. Um yeah thanks uh Russell. So
uh my perspective about like uh
discernment is really about uh judgment
right. So uh we need to the real world
use cases in the especially in the
technology world right we have lot of uh
uh AI tools available especially when
you are when you are uh working on a
solution right there are some tools like
cloud cloud uh code or cursor AI there
are a lot of tools which generally it
generates the code and it also sometimes
builds the entire app but the thing what
we have to do is as a engineer we have
to judge whether it is really building
the solution properly. So the judgment
is really important especially in the
technology world. So I would say this is
more about like the learners have to uh
pause a bit and think about like what
who who created this and and like what's
the evidence supports it right they have
to pause and think before you know
agreeing for certain solutions. So
that's that's the way I would think
about it. H you bring out some good
points there. Um
I guess my followup question Nanda is
um if we look at this from a different
perspective let's say maybe not
information overload but let's say you
know just people like you know firsttime
learners or people that you know have no
idea about AI and they're literally just
treading their toe in the water and then
all of a sudden they just get this flood
of like just
>> so yeah definitely like the new new
learners. I mean the tool give uh it can
give anything right. So and especially
when we are working in an organization
where we have lot of rules and we have
to build certain governance around it
and guard rails around it like before
you accept something. So that way you
know we can prevent something which uh
before you generate and accept
something. So that way you know the
governance body and the architectural
things more important.
>> Mhm. Mhm.
>> something.
>> Well, thank you for sharing your
thoughts, Nanda. And as a trust
architect myself, I completely agree
with what you're saying. Um, so let's go
on to the the next question now. And,
uh, Paulo, we're going to be tagging you
back in. Um, you always have very
interesting insights, so I'm curious to
hear what your thoughts are on this.
What distinctly human capabilities will
grow in v value as automation advances?
And as you know, Paulo, everything is
moving faster and faster rather than
slowing and slowing. So,
>> u I want to uh honor what Stephanie
mentioned first, you know, which is
critical thinking, you know, that's a
human capability that it it's
fundamental to the whole process. Um, I
remember my father
now 92 years old, you know, uh, uh,
teaching me how to use a screwdriver,
you know, when you have the flat one and
you have the Phillips one, the the the
one with the cross the screws.
>> Yeah, I know exactly about,
>> you know, and and and and try to use a
butter knife to open or to unscrew
something, right? I've done that before
as well.
>> Exactly. So he would say to me any work
is easy if you know which tool to use
and how to use the tool correctly.
Right. So again uh in in a in a in a
generation that we are coming into now
with information overload with
automation and all those processes that
are available to us to enrich our lives.
We must never forget that those things
are happening to enrich our lives.
>> In every in every decade, in every
century, there has been uh tools, there
has been innovation, there has been
transformational uh uh aspects in each
industry that at that point people were
like, "Oh my god, are we going to be
replaced? Are we going to be replaced?
Are those things replacing us?" No, the
human mind is still the biggest best
computer. But we must never forget and
that's what I I I quoted Stephanie and
and Zanna is that we must not forget
that our ability to critical think to
question things to to be curious about
things that is the human capability that
AI cannot replace.
>> Totally agree.
>> That's what put us back in control. Uh
just to give a one quick example, I was
with my son at a uh aquarium fish pet
shop yesterday and I took a picture of
this one uh uh uh uh plenario. It's a
mix of aquarium and and plants and
things, you know, and and and and I was
joking with him. I have a super advanced
camera on the cell phone,
>> right? And and I was I was so
disappointed that I could not see on the
camera what I was seeing with my eyes.
And I I I looked at him and I showed him
the picture and I say, "Look at the at
the aquarium. Now tell me how is AI
going to replace us?"
>> That's true. That is true. Because I
mean it makes you think, right? Like
the brain has over 80 billion neurons
within your mind, right? Anywhere
between 80 billion to 120 billion, I
don't know. But the point that I'm
getting at is
>> 112 billion. So I was speaking on my
territory life.
>> But the the the point that what I'm
getting at is
>> the mind has so many neurons and it's
very sophisticated and complicated and
we don't even know everything about the
brain. Right.
>> Yeah. So it's like so it's like how do
we compare that right now with AI
because even AI is still new and
everything right today. So
>> you know it's it's it's like you said
the brain is is is
the most advanced I guess if you want to
call it intelligence right now. Is it
obviously smart like is AI smarter than
a lot of us right now? You could argue
yes. Um, but uh I think the question is
is is I don't think it's really like an
and or. It's more kind of like how is it
going to collaboratively come together
so that we both come together because at
the end of the day as we like to say
Pandora's the box now it's not going to
go go back in. So how do we cultivate it
now so to speak and use it to our
advantage right so to speak or for
humanity in a nutshell. So, so the point
of AI in my perspective and what I see
in my work and with clients and with
friends is that it can make it work
faster because accumulates more
information at one data point at one
place, right? And so it can achieve a
result or you're doing a research or you
you requiring something or you
automating with bots, right? and and it
can make the work faster and simpler for
a person, but you still need the person.
>> So true, true.
>> Going back to what to what Stephanie was
mentioning, we still need to focus
education on teaching people to think by
themselves, to have Davin mentioned that
critical thinking, to have
understanding, to be able to reason
things and comprehend and ask questions.
I remember uh talking to my kids in
school when they were going through
primary school to to to high school and
talking to them you need to have text
comprehension read something ask
questions and understand not just
memorize not just parrot learning so
that's where in terms of distinct human
capabilities that's where we need to put
focus back on
>> well Paulo
>> we need to have intelligent people to
have intelligent AI
>> Paulo I'm gonna have to jump in because
we've run out time. We got two minutes
left. So, um, just to round everything
up, um, first of all, it's been such an
insight, insightful discussion. Thanks
to each and everyone of the panelists on
here today. I want to say that first of
all. Second of all, make sure you go and
follow them on LinkedIn. Uh, go on and
check them out, connect with them, speak
with them, you know, talk about AI stuff
and the future of learning, but also
follow the journey, connect, comment,
etc. as well. So, um, that is it from us
here at Galverse for this round table
discussion. And up next, we're going to
be having a fireside chat coming up in
just a minute, I believe. Um, yes. So,
we our guest is here. So, we're going to
be having the fireside uh chat next. Um,
and that is it for this round of
discussion. So, thank you very much,
panelists, and our gav was well. Thank
you so much.
>> Thank you. Bye.
>> Thank you for the time.
>> Thank you everyone. Bye.
>> Thanks. Bye.
Gavin.
Okay.